

CONTACT



1 (226) 980-9134 Phone Number gsing994@gmail.com Email



www.GurmanSingh.com Website

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Hons) Concentration: Genetics The University of Western Ontario

AWARDS

Next 5% Award - 2019 Released two industry leading software features Advanced Micro Devices

Executive Spotlight - 2018
Directing the largest company
software launch
Advanced Micro Devices

Director Spotlight - 2017Directing the largest company software launch
Advanced Micro Devices

SKILLS

PROCESS MANAGEMENT

SaaS & IaaS BASIC ARCHITECTURE

MARKETING STRATEGY

LRP FORECASTING

ISV RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT

MOBILE APP DEVELOPMENT



Gurman Singh

Product Manager

SUMMARY

An accomplished product management professional with five years of bringing products to market. Experienced in strategy and leading large product releases to drive over 300 million downloads and 200 million total views. Highly organized, detail-oriented, and conscientious self-starter, able to strategize and prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks with creativity, enthusiasm and humor.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



Advanced Micro Devices (AMD) - Product Manager

May 2018 - Present

- Managed graphics optimizations (efficient paging, shader tuning, ML heuristics) for new products driving a 15% gain in GPU product profit margin
- Identified and prioritized key strategic graphics software required to accelerate new IP and increased 30x YoY ROI of operational expenditure (OPEX)
- Collaborated with stakeholders, driving consensus to align on strategic goals based on market analysis
- Created, prioritized and executed on user stories by coordinating ISV engineering and driver development targets thus enabling marketing through technical analysis
- Defined MRDs and PRDs for specialized hardware (VCE) to create consumer-focused products, i.e. streaming and recording software platform
- Roadmapped and prioritized products for the 70+ Radeon Software UX/UI team
- Represented AMD to global partners, showcasing new products and features, fielding questions, providing technical support and collecting feedback on current and future developments

Advanced Micro Devices (AMD) - Product Marketing Specialist

June 2016 - May 2018

- Led five product and software launches gathering over 200 million total views
- Worked with product management to translate technical specifications and industry
 jargon into impactful storytelling used by PR for press releases and investor relations,
 along with social media for message amplification
- Analyzed campaign postmortems to develop recommendations with action items for future releases targeted at creating and improving company-wide KPIs
- Created marketing content for sales enablement, marketing newsletters and customer centric web content
- Represented AMD to champion software releases on world-wide press tours, i.e webcasts, events, press interviews, etc



The University of Western Ontario - Microsoft Account Specialist

January 2015 - May 2016

- Built long term partnerships with customers to identify and sell SaaS and IaaS products
- Drove the adoption of platform services through various channel driven activations
- Recognized as a regional product expert and educated customers on software value



Intercept Group - Microsoft Marketing Lead

August 2013 - December 2014

- Managed a cross-functional team to educate staff and students on Office365 products
- Stimulated product sales by creating and launching promotions for SaaS products
- Led social media marketing campaigns on Facebook and Twitter to increase brand awareness and purchase intent
- Conducted market research to gain valuable customer behavior preferences to better serve customers
- Ensured marketing programs aligned with the overall strategy and vision of Microsoft Canada